# Sunil Dewoolkar

🗣 Mumbai, Maharashtra, India 📓 sunildewoolkar18@gmail.com 🔲 9309571266 🛅 https://in.linkedin.com/in/sunil-dewoolkar-866884193

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in data analysis, identify patterns, and extract actionable insights and information from multiple sources. Worked on stored procedures, data extraction and data manipulation, making customized reports based on SQL.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Application Engineer 2**

**Hewlett Packard** 

August 2022 - Present, Pune

- Working on automation of tasks and tools such AWS redshift.
- AWS s3, SQL, MySQL workbench, GitHub.
- Designing and developing SSIS / SQL ETL solutions to acquire and prepare data from numerous upstream systems.
- Working on optimizing data designs to standardize schemes for optimal performance.

### **Software Engineer**

**Ugam Solutions Pvt. Ltd** 

December 2020 - August 2022, Thane

- Created and deployed stored procedures to support business needs using SQL Server Management Studio.
- Saved time and increased efficiency by automating manual tasks in a retail project.
- · Helped team members to automate tasks.
- Handled a team of 4-5 members.
- Implemented ETL solutions to automate operations at a business process level using Informatica, tidal, AWS redshift, AWS s3, snowflake.
- Designed, developed, and maintained an automated solution used to process invoice data, reducing processing time by 15%. Developed data integration with third-party systems to enable automated data mapping, transforming, and loading resulting in an 80% increase in accuracy. Wrote and tested code, debugged and implemented custom script to support a variety of enterprise applications and scheduled.

### **Technical Support Executive**

Cnergyis Infotech Pvt. Ltd

May 2018 - December 2020, Malad

- Create, Debug and Analyze SQL Queries, Stored Procedures.
- Worked with Executive profile to resolve client problems.
- Improve operations and provide exceptional customer service.
- Done R&D for application testing against attacks (VAPT, Session hijacking, HTML tampering) and resolved issues highlighted.

### Web Developer

**Instinct Innovations Pvt. Ltd** 

November 2017 - April 2018, Malad

• Redbook Website (redbook.co.in) recreation from scratch using HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, and Node.js resulting inimproving overall page load speed from 2s to 500ms and decreasing server resources from 35% to 25%.

# **EDUCATION**

### **Computer Engineering**

VIVA Institute of Technology • 8.5 • 2017

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### DevOps On AWS

Coursera • 2022

# **SKILLS**

SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Apache, Git, Shell Scripting, Redshift